Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and what are we talking about today, Marco?
我是Catherine，Marco，我们今天要聊什么？
Today we are talking about a very interesting topic, most importantly among men who are
今天我们聊一个非常有趣的话题，尤其是对男性来说很重要，
trying to get women's attention.
就是如何吸引女性的注意。
Okay, so these are some of the things that men might try to say if they are trying to
好的，所以这些是一些男性可能会说的话，如果他们试图
find a girlfriend or men if you're out there, things that you might want to say or not want
找女朋友，或者如果你在外面，你可能想用英语说或不想说的一些话。
to say in English.
对，对。
Right, right.
没错。
That's right.
So let's quickly just take a look at our dialogue.
那我们快速看一下对话。
Let's see what's going on and we'll be back in a bit.
看看发生了什么，我们一会儿回来。
Let's go out tomorrow night.
我们明晚出去吧。
We can go to a bar and try to find you a girlfriend.
我们可以去酒吧，帮你找个女朋友。
I don't think that's a good idea.
我觉得这不是个好主意。
I'm just not good with approaching someone and starting up a conversation.
我就是不擅长接近别人并开始对话。
Maybe you just need a few pickup lines, you know, to break the ice.
也许你只需要一些搭讪语，你知道，用来打破僵局。
Pickup lines don't work.
搭讪语不管用。
Come on, you can just walk up to a girl and say, if you were a booger, I'd pick you first.
得了吧，你可以直接走到一个女孩面前说：如果你是鼻屎，我会第一个把你挑出来。
What?
什么？
Come on, that's just lame.
得了吧，那太逊了。
No girl would fall for that.
没有女孩会吃这一套。
Fine, then you can say, so there you are.
好吧，那你可以说：原来你在这儿。
I've been looking all over for you, the woman of my dreams.
我一直在到处找你，我梦中的女人。
That's a good one.
这个不错。
I think that's pretty funny.
我觉得这挺搞笑的。
Yeah, so you make her laugh, you make a fool of yourself a little bit and then you buy
是啊，所以你让她笑，你稍微出点丑，然后你给她
her a drink.
买杯酒。
Okay, how does this sound?
好吧，这个听起来怎么样？
I was so enchanted by your beauty that I ran into that wall over there.
我被你的美貌迷住了，以至于撞到了那边的墙。
So I'm going to need your name and number for insurance purposes.
所以为了保险起见，我需要你的名字和电话号码。
Nice.
不错。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's explain what's going on a little bit more.
现在让我们更详细地解释一下发生了什么。
Let's take a look at some vocab on Language Takeaway.
让我们看看“语言要点”中的一些词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So the first word that we have here, Marco, is a verb.
我们这里的第一个词，Marco，是一个动词。
We say to approach or to approach someone.
我们说“to approach”或“to approach someone”。
That's right, to approach someone.
没错，接近某人。
And that means to go up to someone and start a conversation, start talking to them.
意思是走上前去和某人开始对话，开始和他们交谈。
That's right.
没错。
So you physically walk towards someone, you go to them to start talking to them.
所以你身体上走向某人，去和他们开始交谈。
So you can say, I'm not good at approaching other people or he approached her in the bar
所以你可以说：我不擅长接近别人，或者他在酒吧里接近了她，
because he wanted to talk to her.
因为他想和她说话。
That's right.
没错。
So to approach someone is to go up or get close to that person and start talking to
所以“接近某人”就是走上前或靠近那个人，然后开始和他们
them.
交谈。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So now what the dialogue focuses on is pickup lines, as the title says.
那么对话的重点是搭讪语，正如标题所说。
So what exactly are pickup lines?
那么搭讪语到底是什么？
All right.
好的。
Well, I'll take this as a phrase.
嗯，我会把它当作一个短语来看。
You don't want to look at the individual words, but pickup lines are things that people say
你不应该看单个词，搭讪语是人们说的话，
to show that they are interested romantically in other people.
用来表示他们对别人有浪漫兴趣。
So if I am talking to someone and maybe he says something that is a pickup line, he's
所以如果我在和某人说话，也许他说了一些搭讪语，他是在
trying to show that he's interested in me.
试图表示他对我感兴趣。
That's right.
没错。
So usually, I guess, guys use pickup lines at bars or something to get a girl's attention
所以通常，我想，男人在酒吧之类的地方用搭讪语来吸引女孩的注意，
and to, as you say, show that he is interested in her, right?
并且，如你所说，表示他对她感兴趣，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And some are very creative and nice and some are very stupid and silly.
有些非常有创意和不错，有些则非常愚蠢和傻气。
So there are many different kinds of pickup lines.
所以有很多种不同的搭讪语。
But the trick here is that they're usually lines that the person will create or will
但这里的诀窍是，它们通常是那个人会创造或
have heard before they use it.
之前听过然后使用的句子。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
It's like a fixed thing.
就像固定套路一样。
Yeah.
是的。
It is usually very creative, as you say, or very funny to kind of get the girl's attention.
通常非常有创意，如你所说，或者非常有趣，用来吸引女孩的注意。
Now, the first pickup line that we heard was, if you were a booger, I'd pick you first.
我们听到的第一个搭讪语是：如果你是鼻屎，我会第一个把你挑出来。
If you were a booger, I'd pick you first.
如果你是鼻屎，我会第一个把你挑出来。
All right.
好的。
So what does he mean here?
他这里是什么意思？
If you were a booger, what is a booger?
如果你是鼻屎，鼻屎是什么？
A booger is a piece of dirt in your nose.
鼻屎是你鼻子里的脏东西。
Okay.
好的。
So sometimes you have some things in your nose and you want to blow your nose to clear
所以有时候你鼻子里有些东西，你想擤鼻子来清理
it.
它。
Well, those things inside your nose, those are called boogers.
嗯，你鼻子里的那些东西，叫做鼻屎。
This is very informal English.
这是非常口语化的英语。
Right.
对。
So I guess the technical term for it would be mucus.
所以我想它的专业术语应该是黏液。
Mucus.
黏液。
That's right.
没错。
But obviously, in English, there's also an informal way of calling it and it's called
但显然，在英语里也有一种非正式的说法，叫做
a booger.
鼻屎。
So the idea here is the pickup line means two things.
所以这里的搭讪语有两层意思。
It means sometimes you have to take boogers out of your nose.
一层意思是，有时候你得把鼻屎从鼻子里弄出来。
Some people use their finger.
有些人用手指。
But the other meaning is, if I'm interested in you, I pick you first.
但另一层意思是，如果我对你有兴趣，我会先选你。
And the verb here, to pick, is not to choose, but it's actually used as a verb when you're
这里的动词“pick”，不是“选择”的意思，而是当你
talking about your nose.
谈论鼻子时用的动词。
You pick your nose or you pick a booger.
你挖鼻子或者挖鼻屎。
That means to actually remove.
意思是实际上去除掉。
It means to put your finger in your nose to take out these pieces of dirt.
意思是用手指伸进鼻子里取出这些脏东西。
Right.
对。
So maybe a mom, a mother to their younger son or daughter would tell them, don't pick
所以可能一位妈妈会对她年幼的儿子或女儿说，别在公共场合
your nose in public.
挖鼻子。
Moms often say this in English.
妈妈们经常用英语这么说。
Don't pick your nose.
别挖鼻子。
It's rude.
这很不礼貌。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好了。
So it's a very interesting pickup line.
所以这是一个非常有趣的搭讪语。
Obviously very funny and I guess creative.
显然很搞笑，我觉得也挺有创意的。
But at the same time, the verb there, to pick, we just figured out it means something completely
但同时，那个动词“pick”，我们刚才发现它意思完全
different.
不同。
All right.
好了。
So it's a joke, but it's also kind of gross.
所以这是个玩笑，但也挺恶心的。
Exactly.
没错。
And obviously his friend agrees and says that's lame.
显然他的朋友也同意，并说这很逊。
Lame.
逊。
So something is lame if it's stupid or not funny.
所以如果某件事很蠢或不好笑，就说它很逊。
We often say that's a really lame joke, which means I don't like that.
我们常说那是个很逊的笑话，意思是我不喜欢。
I don't think it's funny.
我觉得不好笑。
Okay.
好的。
And actually people start using the word lame for many things that they don't like or they
实际上人们开始用“逊”这个词来形容很多他们不喜欢或
think is not interesting.
觉得没意思的东西。
Right.
对。
Yeah.
是的。
Like that band is so lame.
比如那个乐队太逊了。
Or that movie was lame.
或者那部电影很逊。
It wasn't interesting.
它不有趣。
It wasn't fun.
它不好玩。
Okay.
好的。
So that's basically what it means.
所以基本上就是这个意思。
All right.
好了。
So let's take a look at everything we've learned again and we'll be back in a bit.
那么让我们回顾一下我们学过的所有内容，我们一会儿再回来。
Let's go out tomorrow night.
我们明晚出去吧。
We can go to a bar and try to find you a girlfriend.
我们可以去酒吧，试着给你找个女朋友。
I don't think that's a good idea.
我觉得这不是个好主意。
I'm just not good with approaching someone and starting up a conversation.
我就是不擅长接近别人并开始对话。
Maybe you just need a few pickup lines, you know, to break the ice.
也许你只需要一些搭讪语，你知道，用来打破僵局。
Pickup lines don't work.
搭讪语没用。
Come on.
得了吧。
You can just walk up to a girl and say, if you were a booger, I'd pick you first.
你可以直接走到一个女孩面前说，如果你是鼻屎，我会第一个选你。
What?
什么？
Come on.
得了吧。
That's just lame.
那太逊了。
No girl would fall for that.
没有女孩会吃这一套。
Fine.
好吧。
Then you can say, so there you are.
那你可以说，原来你在这儿。
I've been looking all over for you, the woman of my dreams.
我一直在到处找你，我梦中的女人。
That's a good one.
这个不错。
I think that's pretty funny.
我觉得这挺搞笑的。
Yeah.
是的。
You know, you make her laugh.
你知道，你让她笑了。
You make a fool of yourself a little bit and then you buy her a drink.
你稍微出点丑，然后给她买杯酒。
Okay.
好的。
How does this sound?
这个听起来怎么样？
I was so enchanted by your beauty that I ran into that wall over there.
我被你的美貌迷住了，以至于撞到了那边的墙。
So I'm going to need your name and number for insurance purposes.
所以我需要你的名字和号码，用于保险目的。
Nice.
不错。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
All right.
好了。
Now, let's take a look at some of these phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在，让我们看看流利度构建器中的一些短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Okay.
好的。
So the first phrase we have here is something very, very common in business as well as in
所以我们这里的第一个短语在商务和社交场合都非常常见。
social situations.
社交场合中。
We say, to break the ice.
我们说，打破僵局。
And this is something that we heard when the two boys were talking about approaching a
这是我们在两个男孩谈论如何接近一个女孩时听到的。
girl.
女孩。
He said, I don't know how to break the ice.
他说，我不知道怎么打破僵局。
Right.
对。
So to break the ice is to make an awkward situation or something that's a little bit
所以打破僵局就是让一个尴尬或有点不舒服的情况变得轻松一些。
uncomfortable, a little bit more relaxed.
更放松一点。
That's right.
没错。
So oftentimes in a new company or at a party where you don't know anyone, you have to break
所以通常在新公司或一个谁也不认识的派对上，你必须打破僵局。
the ice.
打破僵局。
You have to make things more comfortable so you can talk to people.
你必须让事情更舒适，这样你才能和人交谈。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So you want to break the ice.
所以你想打破僵局。
You want to maybe be more comfortable around people.
你想在别人身边更自在一些。
Right.
对。
So sometimes people use games to break the ice.
所以有时人们用游戏来打破僵局。
Like at your company, maybe your first day of work, they'll have games to learn people's
比如在你公司，可能上班第一天，他们会安排游戏来记住大家的名字。
names.
名字。
These are ways of breaking the ice.
这些都是打破僵局的方法。
Or at a party, you learn some pickup lines to break the ice with women.
或者在派对上，你学一些搭讪语来和女生打破僵局。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So we want to break the ice.
所以我们想打破僵局。
We want to use some pickup lines.
我们想用一些搭讪语。
And his friend argues that pickup lines are kind of lame.
他的朋友争辩说搭讪语有点老套。
And he even says, no girl would fall for that line.
他甚至说，没有女孩会相信那种话。
Okay.
好的。
To fall for something.
相信某事。
This is a really important phrase and something that we say often in English.
这是一个非常重要的短语，我们在英语中经常说。
Now, what exactly does it mean?
那么它到底是什么意思呢？
You're not falling on the ground.
你不是真的摔倒在地。
No, no.
不，不。
You believe it or you consider it to be real.
你相信它，或者认为它是真的。
All right.
好的。
So when something is a lie or it's fake or it's not totally true, but someone believes
所以当某件事是谎言、假的或不完全真实，但有人还是相信了，你就说那个人上当了。
it anyway, you say that that person, he fell for it.
他上当了。
Okay.
好的。
So if I say, hey, Marco, did you know tomorrow's a holiday?
所以如果我说，嘿，Marco，你知道明天是假期吗？
We don't have to work.
我们不用上班。
Okay.
好的。
And I don't come to work.
然后我不来上班。
Yeah.
嗯。
I say, oh, Marco fell for my trick.
我说，哦，Marco 中了我的圈套。
I mean, he believed it, but I was actually lying.
我的意思是，他相信了，但我其实在撒谎。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So to fall for something means to believe it or to think it's true.
所以“fall for something”意思是相信它或认为它是真的。
Yeah.
嗯。
So no girl would fall for that means no girl would actually like you because you use these
所以“没有女孩会相信”意思是，没有女孩会真的喜欢你，因为你用了这些傻乎乎的搭讪语。
silly pickup lines.
这些傻乎乎的搭讪语。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So then he actually used another line.
然后他实际上用了另一句搭讪语。
He said, okay, so maybe you can use this other line.
他说，好吧，也许你可以用这句。
And his friend agreed.
他的朋友同意了。
Okay.
好的。
That's a good one.
这句不错。
You can also say good one.
你也可以说“好主意”。
Good one.
好主意。
Yeah.
嗯。
This is very informal English.
这是非常非正式的英语。
We say when we want to say that, you know, I like the idea or it's a good, it's a good
当我们想说，你知道，我喜欢这个主意，或者这是个好主意时，我们会这么说。
idea.
好主意。
Or maybe even a joke.
或者甚至是个笑话。
Someone tells a joke and you think it's really funny.
有人讲了个笑话，你觉得很好笑。
You say, oh, that's a good one.
你说，哦，这个不错。
That's a good one.
这个不错。
So in this case, we heard one good pickup line and one bad one, but maybe you're at
所以在这个例子里，我们听到了一句好的搭讪语和一句差的，但也许你在工作中，有人想出了一个很好的营销点子。
work and someone comes up with a really good idea for marketing.
营销点子。
You say, oh, that's a good one.
你说，哦，这个不错。
That's a good idea.
这是个好主意。
That's a good one.
这个不错。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
And obviously his friend explains that the whole purpose of the pickup line is to make
显然他的朋友解释说，搭讪语的整个目的是让你自己出点丑，然后，你知道，给女孩买杯饮料或者成为她的。
a fool of yourself a little bit and then, you know, buy the girl a drink or become her
成为她的。
friend.
朋友。
Okay.
好的。
To make a fool of yourself.
让自己出丑。
Now, this is something that is probably not a good thing in most cases, right?
这通常不是什么好事，对吧？
A fool is someone who is silly, who no one takes seriously.
傻瓜就是那种傻乎乎、没人当回事的人。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
Someone who's not, yeah, not very serious.
就是那种不太严肃的人。
So to make a fool of yourself is to embarrass yourself a little bit.
所以“让自己出丑”就是让自己有点尴尬。
Yeah.
是的。
To look stupid in front of other people.
在别人面前显得很蠢。
So I can say, oh, on my first day of work, I tripped and I fell on the ground and I made
所以我可以这么说，哦，我上班第一天，绊了一跤摔在地上，在
a fool of myself in front of my new colleagues.
新同事面前出了丑。
That's right.
没错。
So that's basically what it means to make a fool of yourself, to embarrass yourself,
所以“让自己出丑”基本上就是这个意思，让自己尴尬，
but you're doing it to yourself.
但这是你自己造成的。
It's not that someone else is embarrassing you.
不是别人让你尴尬。
You are embarrassing yourself.
是你自己让自己尴尬。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好了。
Let's try that dialogue one last time and we'll be back in a bit.
我们最后再听一遍那段对话，然后马上回来。
Let's go out tomorrow night.
我们明晚出去吧。
We can go to a bar and try to find you a girlfriend.
我们可以去酒吧，试着给你找个女朋友。
I don't think that's a good idea.
我觉得这不是个好主意。
I'm just not good with approaching someone and starting up a conversation.
我就是不擅长接近别人并开始聊天。
Maybe you just need a few pickup lines, you know, to break the ice.
也许你只需要几句搭讪语，你知道的，用来打破僵局。
Pickup lines don't work.
搭讪语不管用。
Come on.
别这样。
You can just walk up to a girl and say, if you were a booger, I'd pick you first.
你可以直接走到一个女孩面前说：“如果你是个鼻屎，我会第一个把你挑出来。”
What?
什么？
Come on.
别这样。
That's just lame.
那太逊了。
No girl would fall for that.
没有女孩会吃这一套。
Fine.
好吧。
Then you can say, so there you are.
那你可以说：“原来你在这儿。”
I've been looking all over for you, the woman of my dreams.
“我一直在到处找你，我梦中的女人。”
That's a good one.
这个不错。
I think that's pretty funny.
我觉得挺搞笑的。
Yeah.
是的。
So you make her laugh.
所以你让她笑了。
You make a fool of yourself a little bit and then you buy her a drink.
你让自己有点出丑，然后给她买杯饮料。
Okay.
好的。
How does this sound?
这个听起来怎么样？
I'm so enchanted by your beauty that I ran into that wall over there.
“我被你的美貌迷住了，以至于撞到了那边那堵墙。”
So I'm going to need your name and number for insurance purposes.
“所以我需要你的名字和号码，用于保险理赔。”
Nice.
不错。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
All right.
好的。
So looking at these pickup lines, we took a look at the first one about the booger and
所以看看这些搭讪语，我们看了第一个关于鼻屎的，
everything.
还有其他的。
What about the second one when you say, so there you are.
第二个呢，当你说：“原来你在这儿。”
I've been looking all over for you, the woman of my dreams.
“我一直在到处找你，我梦中的女人。”
So what is he saying here?
他在这里说什么？
What is it?
这是什么意思？
What is implied?
暗示了什么？
He's basically saying that he's met her before and he's been looking for her.
他基本上是在说，他以前见过她，一直在找她。
So where did he meet her?
那他在哪里见过她？
He says he met her in his dreams, but now, oh, there she is.
他说他在梦里见过她，但现在，哦，她就在那儿。
I was looking for you.
“我一直在找你。”
You, you're the woman of my dreams.
“你，你就是我梦中的女人。”
Right.
对。
So obviously the girl can feel a little bit confused at first because, oh, why were you
所以显然女孩一开始会有点困惑，因为，哦，你为什么
looking for me?
在找我？
And then he says, oh, because you are the woman of my dreams.
然后他说，哦，因为你是我梦中的女人。
So it's obviously a little bit exaggerating, but it's funny.
所以这显然有点夸张，但很有趣。
He's joking, but he's basically saying, you know, I know you, I've been looking for you.
他在开玩笑，但他基本上是在说，你知道，我认识你，我一直在找你。
And what about our last, uh, pickup line where he was saying, I was so enchanted by your
那我们最后一个搭讪语呢，他说：“我被你的美貌迷住了，
beauty that I ran into that wall over there.
以至于撞到了那边那堵墙。”
So I am going to need your name and number for insurance purposes.
“所以我需要你的名字和号码，用于保险理赔。”
So he's saying, you're so beautiful that I had this accident.
所以他在说，你太美了，以至于我出了这个意外。
I walked into a wall, I hit my face.
我撞到了墙，撞到了脸。
Now that I have an injury, I need your information so that I can claim insurance so I can get
现在我受伤了，我需要你的信息，这样我才能申请保险，才能从
money from my insurance company.
我的保险公司拿到钱。
So this is a way to ask a woman for her phone number and name.
所以这是一种向女人要电话号码和名字的方式。
Her name.
她的名字。
Exactly.
没错。
So it's a very clever way of, uh, of, of, of obviously breaking the ice, but at the
所以这是一种非常聪明的方式，呃，用来打破僵局，但同时
same time, he's trying to be funny and trying to get her number, her telephone number and
他也在试图搞笑，并试图拿到她的号码，她的电话号码和
her name.
她的名字。
That's right.
没错。
So one of the most memorable ones that I've heard was, uh, was your father a thief because
我听过最难忘的一个是，呃，你爸爸是不是小偷，因为
he stole the stars from the sky and put them in your eyes.
他把天上的星星摘下来放进了你的眼睛里。
Ah, nice.
啊，不错。
So, uh, this one is more of a compliment.
所以，呃，这个更像是一种赞美。
Yes, it's a compliment.
是的，这是一种赞美。
And uh, but in a funny way saying, oh, your dad stole all the stars from the sky.
而且，呃，用一种有趣的方式说，哦，你爸爸偷走了天上所有的星星。
Yeah, no, I've heard a number of them.
是啊，我听过不少这样的。
Most of them are pretty bad, pretty lame.
大部分都很糟糕，很蹩脚。
Um, and they're always a, a way to almost always a way to ask for your phone number.
嗯，它们几乎总是，几乎总是用来要你电话号码的方式。
Now as a girl, what do you think is better for a guy to use a clever, funny, but tasteful
作为一个女孩，你觉得男生用哪种方式更好：用一句聪明、有趣但得体的
pickup line or to just walk up to you and say, hi, my name is so and so.
搭讪语，还是直接走到你面前说，嗨，我叫某某某。
You know, what's your name?
你知道，你叫什么名字？
If you can be clever, if you can come up with something that's funny or interesting, then
如果你能聪明点，能想出一些有趣或有意思的话，那么
I think it's good.
我觉得挺好的。
If you say something that's rude or disgusting, I think that's probably bad.
如果你说些粗鲁或恶心的话，我觉得那可能很糟糕。
Like the booger, the booger pickup line is a bad idea.
比如那个鼻屎，鼻屎搭讪语就是个坏主意。
That's an example of a bad pickup line.
那是一个糟糕搭讪语的例子。
But you know, if you can laugh about it, not, you don't say it seriously, but if you can
但你知道，如果你能笑着面对，不是，你不是认真地说，而是如果你能
laugh about it and say, hey, you know, is your daddy a thief?
笑着问，嘿，你知道，你爸爸是小偷吗？
It's something to start the conversation if you're laughing.
如果你在笑，这就能开启对话。
Right.
对。
Because sometimes it's very awkward if someone says, hey, I'm John, you know, what's your
因为有时候会很尴尬，如果有人直接说，嘿，我是约翰，你知道，你叫什么
name?
名字？
Right.
对。
You don't really know how to react to that.
你真的不知道该怎么回应。
It's a little boring.
有点无聊。
And, and approaching someone like that way can be a little bit difficult.
而且，用那种方式接近别人可能会有点困难。
Yeah.
是啊。
It's a very interesting thing.
这是一件非常有趣的事。
Let us know if you have any pickup lines, if you've heard any pickup lines or used any.
如果你有任何搭讪语，或者听过或用过任何搭讪语，请告诉我们。
We're really curious to know.
我们真的很好奇。
Yeah.
是啊。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you guys there.
我们希望能在那里见到你们。
All right guys.
好了，各位。
Thanks for listening.
谢谢收听。